<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>De Wet Blomerus</title>
    <description>I built this website in Jekyll &amp; hosting it on Github Pages.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 14:56:35 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 14:56:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I used VirtualBox snapshots to create my ultimate Linux post install script</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-have-always-wanted-a-really-awesome-linux-post-install-script-to-automatically-install-and-set-up-everything-i-need-to-start-being-a-productive-web-developer-within-an-hour-after-installing-linux&quot;&gt;I have always wanted a really awesome Linux post install script to automatically install and set up everything I need to start being a productive web developer within an hour after installing Linux.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a few reasons for this:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s cool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I saw thoughtbot created an OSX laptop script (aka, it’s cool)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t like doing tedious, repetitive tasks, which is also why I love programming.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It breaks focus when I am in the middle of coding something and I need to apt-get install some dependancy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Installing stuff manually can waste a lot of time, because while I wait for it to download or install I can get distracted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have taught a lot of people to code and really love getting people started. Windows is great but I don’t do development on it, so if you want to “follow me” then I will help you set up your Linux environment so that it is ready to start coding. This means I actually get to use my install script quite often.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It gives me the freedom to try out different distros whenever I want. As long as I install Linux at the end of the day and set my script to run, I don’t lose any time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One challenge I always had with not getting my install script tuned quite the way I needed it, was that even while running a bootcamp, I use it less than once per week. So if I needed 25 iterations to get it where I wanted it, that’s over half a year. The other problem is that if something fails halfway through installing things, you can’t fix it and see it working in it’s fixed state, you have to fix it and wait for next time to see the results, which kills motivation. I was slowly making my way through this process with no end in sight when I got annoyed and decided to solve this once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-virtualbox-snapshots&quot;&gt;Enter, VirtualBox Snapshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like Git for a Virtual Machine. It allowed me take a couple of hours and run my script many times over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the steps I took:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Linux Mint in a VirtualBox (I switched from Ubuntu to Mint as my main distro this year).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a Snapshot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run my script.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When something fails I fix the part of the script that caused it to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restore to the snapshot. (This is instant on an SSD).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat steps 3-5 until the whole thing runs without any problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my current post-install script. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dewetblomerus/linux-laptop&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;linux-laptop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/24/how-i-used-virtualbox-snapshots-to-create-my-ultimate-linux-post-install-script.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/24/how-i-used-virtualbox-snapshots-to-create-my-ultimate-linux-post-install-script.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using VCR 3 with Rails 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All the guides on using VCR with Rails that I found in my googling was from 2012 or older. This ended up being super easy but I still ended up wasting time trying to find a newer reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put this in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;group :test do
  gem &#39;vcr&#39;
  gem &#39;webmock&#39;
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put the following in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;spec/spec_helper.rb&lt;/code&gt;
    require ‘vcr’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;VCR.configure do |c|
  c.cassette_library_dir = &#39;spec/cassettes&#39;
  c.hook_into :webmock
  c.configure_rspec_metadata!
end

RSpec.configure do |config|
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then finally. In the specs that make the web requests you want to record, put &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;, :vcr do&lt;/code&gt; right after the description&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/21/using-vcr-3-with-rails-4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/21/using-vcr-3-with-rails-4.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Catalog of Refactorings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is so cool. I would really like to see a page like this with every technical book I read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.refactoring.com/catalog/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Catalog of Refactorings by Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/01/refactoring-catalog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/03/01/refactoring-catalog.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Backup Dotfiles to Github</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I was creating some aliases in my .zshrc to quickly create new posts, I realized that the file has grown into something that I quite like and I really don’t want to re-make from scratch ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also that moment when you know you should spend a few minutes in one of your .dotfiles sharpening your productivity tools, but you don’t want to really bother. I think knowing that I have a backup system in place and that whatever time I invest in my .dotfiles is something I can draw dividents from for the rest of my “Linux Hacking Life”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found an excellent post, telling me exactly how to set this up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.smalleycreative.com/tutorials/using-git-and-github-to-manage-your-dotfiles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Using Git And Github To Manage Your Dotfiles&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Smalley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the approach he took and was happy to follow it step by step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were just two small gotchas that I figured out quite quickly but it is the type of thing that one can get stuck on &amp;amp; give up the whole process, so here they are, hopefully you or my future self will find them helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;makemysimlinks.sh&lt;/code&gt; script is a tiny bit scary, but ended up being 100% fine.
It copied the directories belonging to zshell &amp;amp; vim to a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dotfiles_old&lt;/code&gt; directory in the home directory. Because I didn’t read the script before running it (I know, very irresponsible) I was expecting the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dotfiles_old&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/dotfiles&lt;/code&gt; directory. So for a minute there my Vim wasn’t working properly &amp;amp; I didn’t know where the directory went.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/code&gt; installation directory is a Git repo
The way I installed Zshell on Ubuntu was by cloning the Git repository. I really like this method of installation because whenever I want to update it I just cd into it and do a git pull.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I dealt with a Git repo inside a Git repo. I added it to a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; and did a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git rm -r --cached &amp;lt;your directory&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to stop tracking it and all was well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that all was working perfectly, my dotfiles &amp;amp; relevant directories are now pushed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dewetblomerus/dotfiles&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a git repo here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would suggest you do the same, it will take you way less time to set this up than to have to keep stopping in the middle of your work to go add things to your dotfiles that you forgot when you moved to your new machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/02/29/backup-dotfiles-to-github.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/02/29/backup-dotfiles-to-github.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My first post on Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am typing my first post in Sublime Text. Oh my word this feels so much better than blogging in wp-admin. The 30 seconds I save by not having to load a web page &amp;amp; log in “feels” like it makes a difference, wow we humans are terrible at guaging time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 09:13:17 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blogging/2016/02/26/my-first-post-on-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blogging/2016/02/26/my-first-post-on-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why learn to program?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I stumbled on this Lifehacker post &quot;Don&#39;t Learn to Code: Learn to Work With Technology&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there are two schools of thought here. Readers &amp;amp; Mechanics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a &quot;Readers&quot; view of coding is to believe learning to code is like reading. You can make it though life without it. Especially if you live somewhere in central Africa with hot weather &amp;amp; fertile soil so you can farm the land you live on to provide for yourself &amp;amp; your family. People might say &quot;learning to read would be useful &amp;amp; make trips to town more convenient, but it is really difficult, frustrating &amp;amp; time consuming, I am living just fine without knowing how to read, so it is not necessary&quot;. As a reader, when we see this, we think &quot;oh no, you don&#39;t get it, if you only knew the power &amp;amp; freedom literacy would give you, you would start today, but it is really damn frustrating to learn how to read, so I won&#39;t be the one to try and convince you it&#39;s necessary&quot;. Readers generally believe that since so much of our work is done using computers, being able to automate the inefficient bits of what we do &quot;Just makes sense&quot;. Why would you rename files one by one? Why test the contact from on your wordpress website manually? Learning to code makes you more efficient at many daily tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a &quot;Mechanic&quot; view of coding is to think learning to code is like fixing a car. Your car breaks. Who should fix it? I was born in 1983 so my first car had fuel injection, sensors to measure all kinds of things &amp;amp; a computer to read the data &amp;amp; calculate how much fuel to inject at any moment. Knowing which gear the automatic gearbox should be in was also calculated by a computer. This code wasn&#39;t open sourced, Chevrolet didn&#39;t even give me a REST API or documentation!!!!!!!! Fact, if things broke on the car, I could not fix all of it. I could not do what my dad did 30 years before and take whole cars apart &amp;amp; put it back together in working order. Fact, I didn&#39;t want to be a career mechanic. So I did some calculations of my own, I calculated that I would take at least twice as long as a decent mechanic to fix my car, so if I could just earn half as much money as I would pay for a mechanic working on my car, then I am wasting money (opportunity cost of what I could be making) when I work on my car myself. So I decided that until mechanics went into extremely high demand &amp;amp; labor on cars went up exponentially, I will not waste the money (opportunity cost) of working on my car ever again. Unless I was in a position where I am broke or jobless &amp;amp; I need to fix the car before I can go turn hours into money (which has happened a few times). Taking a Mechanic view of coding is to believe that since other people code for a living, they can use the resulting software &amp;amp; focus on what they are good at. Like owning a car &amp;amp; not needing to know how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see merit in both but lean toward the reader mentality. I see the world heading into a direction where being code literate would be useful in more and more situations. Even just knowing what is possible with code &amp;amp; which kinds of jobs should be done by humans &amp;amp; which kinds of jobs should be done by computers. Being able to imagine what kind of custom software would be required to make you more efficient. Even if you don&#39;t work on the car yourself, you will one day own one or be responsible for getting one built or fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 19:49:46 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/10/16/why-learn-to-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/10/16/why-learn-to-program.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>rspec test javascript</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I volunteered at &lt;a href=&quot;https://railsbridgecapetown.org/&quot;&gt;Railsbridge&lt;/a&gt; yesterday &amp;amp; when the other teachers didn&#39;t seem busy enough I went ahead &amp;amp; asked them questions of my own. I learned about the save_and_open_page method in Rspec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gave me the power to go fix a bunch of feature tests that I previously couldn&#39;t figure out how to fix, usually the features were working but the tests were failing falsely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I got to one that got the better of me again. It was a page that loaded a &quot;Flash&quot; message but didn&#39;t reload the page. I asked for help again and someone explained to me that the Silenium Web Driver that is the default web driver for Rspec isn&#39;t capable of seeing these sort of Javascript changes to the page if it doesn&#39;t reload, it only inspects HTML but doesn&#39;t launch a full headless web browser. What I needed was a gem called &#39;poltergeist&#39; which would let me use phantomjs which would give me this capability. Here is how I fixed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install PhantomJS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://gist.github.com/julionc/7476620&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switch from Selenium to Poltergeist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://everydayrails.com/2015/01/27/rspec-switch-selenium-poltergeist.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, since phantomjs will be running in a different thread, unexpected things could happen in the test database. Here is a post by Avdi that explains how &amp;amp; why to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://devblog.avdi.org/2012/08/31/configuring-database_cleaner-with-rails-rspec-capybara-and-selenium/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I could finish the last step I noticed that something else was wrong with the spec, I forgot to let it click a link. So now my tests are fixed and this process is not done, but hopefully writing it down for when I do need it will make it less painful at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 13:09:20 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/20/rspec-test-javascript.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/20/rspec-test-javascript.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I got the error messages from Cron</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I needed to use Cron to run a script on regular intervals. I quickly realized that running code without error messages was no fun &amp;amp; I needed to see what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There must have been a way to write it to a log but it seems like the way people usually handle error messages from Cron is via sending an email, so that&#39;s what I went for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed this post &amp;amp; got it working&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.howtogeek.com/51819/how-to-setup-email-alerts-on-linux-using-gmail/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting my error messages emailed to me helped me find my mistake &amp;amp; now my script works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 20:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/31/how-i-got-the-error-messages-from-cron.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/31/how-i-got-the-error-messages-from-cron.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Wordpress to Developer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I got this question from a friend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I have a passion for design and basic UX. Not really into coding but know that I&#39;ll have to start that venture sooner than later. Really cool that you&#39;re doing ruby as a ministry. I&#39;m studying with Udemy currently and enjoying it. I&#39;m very comfortable with Wordpress and designing websites in this platform. Would love your input on what you think I&#39;d need to be a successful web designer/developer?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello friend, here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take courage, you are a long way on your way if you can already build Wordpress websites. Take Warning, learning how to code never stops, it is long, hard frustrating work, and the small successes are addictive because when you work that hard for success you really feel it, so while you are a long way on your way, going down this road means you will always feel like you don&#39;t know enough.... but you do get to learn new things every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am assuming currently you can do the whole thing yourself. A client can come to you and ask for what they want in a website, you lock yourself in a room, and come out with a website. Unfortunately the one-man-band thing is probably a long ways off for you &amp;amp; Rails. Could you tackle one piece at a time? First aim to do the front end design on a Rails App? Here is what I think you would need to do for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use one of the example apps here https://github.com/RailsApps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to keep calling Rails Websites &quot;Apps&quot; because it makes me feel like a real programmer. Your first challenge is just to get the app installed on your machine or on Cloud9 if you use Windows (installing Rails on Windows is a challenge that Rails developers tend to shy away from) we all do Linux or Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe go through the beginning of a Rails Tutorial to figure out the basics of what is what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t yet worry about the fact that you can only make the app that the tutorial tells you to, just focus on &quot;having an app&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you learn Bootsrap or Foundation (front end frameworks) and figure out how to use those frameworks to design a Rails app &amp;amp; make it beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use Git from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find a developer like me, who knows how to make things work, but don&#39;t have a clue how to make it look nice, and team up with them to make an app for a client. Even though you are splitting the money between at least two people you should still be getting paid more than doing the equivalent work in Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m De Wet Blomerus, If you are not a computer I trust you can figure out how to get in touch with me to ask some questions if you have any.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 20:41:56 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/27/wordpress-and-designing-websites-in-this-platform-would-love-your-input-on-what-you-think-id-need-to-be-a-successful-web-designerdeveloper.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/27/wordpress-and-designing-websites-in-this-platform-would-love-your-input-on-what-you-think-id-need-to-be-a-successful-web-designerdeveloper.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where I put environment variables</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my .profile file....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because that&#39;s the way I roll!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 19:45:13 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/17/where-i-put-environment-variables.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/17/where-i-put-environment-variables.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
