<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>De Wet Blomerus</title>
    <description>Built with Jekyll &amp; hosted on Github Pages.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 16:03:19 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 16:03:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The sweetspot Toptal seems to fill</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is my take on some different services for finding consulting clients, and why I am currently applying to get into Toptal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upwork.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Upwork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not bad. I have done some work on there and have dealt with some really friendly and thankful clients. But since anyone in the world can sign up right now and call themselves a developer and list their price as lower than yours, it&#39;s hard to charge good prices there. Also, because it is seen as &quot;budget outsourcing&quot;, it is often used as such. Many of the clients on there are wanting software built that would be &quot;nice to have&quot;, they don&#39;t see the software as an essential part of their business, if it was, they would be looking somewhere else where they would be taking less risk.

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letsworkshop.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Cool service. There just wasn&#39;t enough Ruby jobs for me. At the time I was also looking for contracts and not for a full time position, and most of the Ruby postings were job postings, which I wasn&#39;t looking for at the time. I am more open to a full time position now so I will probably give this service a try again in the future.

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devchat.tv/freelancers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Starting Your Own Company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This definitely has the potential of making more money. But personally, I&#39;d rather make less money and outsource my marketing and brand recognition work. I know it might seem lazy but I would rather put that effort into becoming a better programmer, later down the road I can monetize on that by solving massively expensive and difficult problems that I am an expert at solving.

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.toptal.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toptal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Toptal has already done a lot of the hard work for me as a developer, by building a brand that clients trust. They also do a lot of the hard work for the client, by having a rigorous interview process before a developer or designer can be listed on the site. Toptal seems to occupies a sweet spot for me here in that I get some of the benefits that would come from a trusted brand that I had to build myself, and some of the benefits of an outsourcing website where I can just go sign up and find clients. I am currently in the application process so I will let you know how it turns out and if it lives up to my expectations.

&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/08/the-sweetspot-toptal-seems-to-fill.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/08/the-sweetspot-toptal-seems-to-fill.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I Symlinked Every Folder In My Home Directory</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../assets/post-images/symlinks-screenshot.png&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-i-dont-have-a-home-folder-partition&quot;&gt;Why I don’t have a home folder partition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think that the problem I am solving here can very easily be solved by creating a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;home&lt;/code&gt; folder partition. It’s dead simple and well documented, what can go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, my personal preference is to keep my installation on my laptop as long as possible. From the time 14.04 was released until close to the time 16.04 was released I worked every day on the exat same installation of 14.04. So if I am going to reinstall the OS, I have a reason for LEAVING my current installation and putting an end to the relationship. If I had a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt; partition I would then need to decide which things are settings I want to throw away, which hidden config files might be a part of my reason for leaving. Or I need to format it, which totally defeats the purpose of having it. So when I reinstall I NUKE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-didnt-want-to-move-my-stuff-around-anymore&quot;&gt;I didn’t want to move my stuff around anymore&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the comfort and freedom that comes from getting to set up my entire development environment with a script, it works great and &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/04/24/how-i-used-virtualbox-snapshots-to-create-my-ultimate-linux-post-install-script.html&quot;&gt;here is how I did it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lets me completely set up a development environment anywhere in a couple of minutes and my own laptop can have everything installed within an hour after reinstalling the OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week I benefited from this twice. The first time when I upgraded to Linux Mint 18. The second time when I discovered a weird triple monitor bug that was introduced in Mint 18 so I installed Ubuntu 16.04 which I am now happily using. I am not married to either, for me an operating system needs to be boring, free, have-built-in-window-management-keyboard-shortcuts and let me install everything with scripts. I am much more interested in what I can create with it than what favor of Linux I’m using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was that every time I need to reinstall I need to move all my stuff, and because I have many tiny files, they go slow even over SATA. Last night I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PJjHfa5yxlU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;watched a talk by Sandy Metz&lt;/a&gt; which made me think of my problem as a coupling problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-data-and-my-methods-were-coupled-too-tightly&quot;&gt;My data and my methods were coupled too tightly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the applications on the computer, acting on the data is like methods or functions, and the data is all the stuff I need to keep and bring to the next installation, I needed a way to decouple this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heres-what-i-did&quot;&gt;Here’s what I did&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal with these instructions is to create a separate partition on my SSD where I keep all my ‘homy?’ stuff but the OS does not mout it as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt; it is just mounted as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;media/dewet/ssd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Here are the partitions I created during installation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;17 gig /swap #I have 16 gigs ram and want the option to hibernate with 10 vm&#39;s running if I felt like it
30 gig / #Linux creates all of it&#39;s stuff in here, including my home folder
the rest of the ssd /media/dewet/ssd #I could ignore this and do it later by partitioning with disk utility and setting the mount point with `fstab` but the option is in the install gui
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Then after installing I delete every directory in my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;home&lt;/code&gt; folder except for my Desktop which Ubuntu didn’t allow and I don’t care becasue I don’t usually keep stuff there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Copy all of my backed up Home folder to the root of the partition mounted at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/media/dewet/ssd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Run this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;S=(bin code dewetblomerus.github.io Documents Downloads Dropbox Music Pictures Public Templates Videos VirtualBox-VMs);
SSDPATH=/media/dewet/ssd
for i in ${FOLDERS[@]}
do
  rm -f ~/$i
  ln -s $SSDPATH/$i ~/$i
done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is an Array and a For loop in Bash that creates Symlinks. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rm&lt;/code&gt; deletes the symlinks if they exist which makes the script idempotent and potentially dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This file is a part of my whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dewetblomerus/linux-laptop&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;laptop setup script repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/07/why-i-symlinked-every-folder-in-my-home-directory.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/07/why-i-symlinked-every-folder-in-my-home-directory.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why not to learn Microsoft Office</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Few people know what programming is so people usually just see me as a “Computer Person”. Here is a great xkcd comic explaining
&lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/627/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;how I am able to be a “Computer Person”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I was asked about good material for learning Microsoft Office, here is my answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Office is a great general purpose tool, but I believe it makes a poor subject for study. I think everyone needs to be able to do the basics. Write up a document in Word, drop in a picture or two if needed and please keep the aspect ratio. Write down a bunch of numbers in Excel and add them together. Save your files, find them on the hard drive, and attach them to an email, you have now graduated the De Wet Blomerus Office Curriculum. After that, it is much more important to learn how to use Google to solve problems. There are a couple reasons I believe this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employability&lt;/strong&gt;
If an employer or customer is going to pay somoene good money to design some sort of a flyer or document, they will be wanting someone to do it in graphic design software like Indesign, Illustrator or Photoshop, if you want that job, study graphic design, it should include studies of whatever software is needed. If an employer is going to pay someone to do things in Excell, they will want somone who knows something about Business or Finance or Administration. If you want one of those jobs, study Business or Finance or Administration, your studies will include the necessary Excell.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope&lt;/strong&gt;
The Microsoft Office Suite is a broad general set of tools, in order to be useful to every business on the planet, they have tons and tons of features. Each type of business only uses maybe 5% of these features, I know what you are thinking, you want to learn the essential 5%, no you can’t because different businesses would use a different 5%. If you successfully learned how to use 100% of the features in the Microsoft Office Suite, 95% of your skills will go to waste because your job will only require the 5%.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to Google, it’s a better skill to have&lt;/strong&gt;
On more than one occasion I have had to use some crazy advanced Microsoft Office (or Libre Office in my case) feature. Every time I need to do this, I use my one computer skill that I can apply to every job, I Google something like “How do I take names and addresses from an Excel Spreadsheet and print out address labels”. Then I find very specific instructions, sometimes I even find a Youtube video with someone showing and explaining exactly what I need to do. Why would you spend the time to learn and store Microsoft Office features in my head when I can just Google and find the exact instructions on what to do?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to Touch Type, it’s a better skill to have&lt;/strong&gt;
Now here is a skill that way too many people overlook. This blog post didn’t take very long at all because it is coming through my fingers quite fast. 100% of all jobs I have ever seen working at a comptuer, can be done faster with better touch typing. If you are still looking at your fingers while you type, stop reading this right now, install a Typing Tutor. &lt;a href=&quot;http://klavaro.sourceforge.net/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Klavaro&lt;/a&gt; is free and works great. I have NEVER seen someone practice touch typing for one hour per day for a whole month and not able to touch type at the end of the month, but even if you are the slowest learner on earth and it took you 3 months of one hour per day each day, it will still be a worthwhile investment from which you will reap the benefits for the rest of your life, every time you use a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/04/why-not-to-learn-microsoft-office.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/04/why-not-to-learn-microsoft-office.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vim cheat sheet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Always up to date, personal vim cheat sheet, you should totally make one like this for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th class=&quot;tablename&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Working on&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Mapping&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Summary&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;move (&lt;strong&gt;b&lt;/strong&gt;)ackward one word&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;move forward to the (&lt;strong&gt;e&lt;/strong&gt;)nd a word&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;f&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;f&lt;/strong&gt;)ind a character forward in a line and move to it&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;t&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;find a character forward in a line and move un(&lt;strong&gt;t&lt;/strong&gt;)il it (one character before)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;F&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;f&lt;/strong&gt;)ind a character backward in a line and move to it&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;T&amp;lt;char&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;find a character backward in a line and move un(&lt;strong&gt;t&lt;/strong&gt;)il it&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;repeat last &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;t&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt; command&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;repeat last &lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;t&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt; command, but in opposite direction&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th class=&quot;tablename&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;To work on one day&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Mapping&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Summary&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;H&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;M&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;L&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;move (&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;)igh, (&lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;)iddle, or (&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;)ow within the viewport&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-u&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;C-d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;move (&lt;strong&gt;u&lt;/strong&gt;)p or (&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;)own&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;NN&amp;gt;G&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;)o to line number NN (useful if you have a failing test on a given line)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th class=&quot;tablename&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Already Mastered&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Mapping&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Summary&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;search&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;repeat last search&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;repeat last search in opposite direction&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;move up/down one line&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;move left/right by character&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;move forward one (&lt;strong&gt;w&lt;/strong&gt;)ord&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;esc&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Exit out of any mode back into normal mode&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;:q&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:quit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Quit out of Vim&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;:w&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:write&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Write the current file&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Move the cursor down / up&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Move the cursor left / right&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Go into &amp;quot;insert mode&amp;quot; to enter text&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Delete the character under the cursor&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/06/30/vim-cheat-sheet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/06/30/vim-cheat-sheet.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You are never too experienced for Codeacademy or Codeschool</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been coding for 5 years now. Several of my bootcamp students have gone on to start full time web development positions the week after they graduate with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These successes are great, but I got here by learning Linux, Ruby and Rails in that order, and learning each of them well before moving to the next step. This gives me a confidence when working with Ruby code inside or outside of Rails that I would LOVE to have when making changes on the front end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I decided it was time to truly learn CSS and Javascript, my Ego failed me and I thought to myself “I’m too advanced for Codeschool or Codeacademy” I need something where I can work only in the terminal to learn this thing from first principles, learning from the bottom up, master the building blocks and get super quick feedback by not using a stupid gui especially not one that slowly loads in the browser. If I was going to do a course I should do &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pluralsight&lt;/a&gt; like real developers do, but even then, the only sensible thing to do would be to leverage my ninja mouseless navigation skills to Vim and Terminal the shit out of this thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while there was some wisdom sprinkled around this, the ego kept me from seeing the “Use the right tool for the job” principle that started screaming at me pretty early on in the command line javascript interpreter world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Codeacademy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeschool.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Codeschool&lt;/a&gt; are tools built for exactly this. I didn’t know Javascript or CSS. I would pattern match and move code around and copy-paste from stack overflow but I didn’t know these like I know Ruby. No matter how experienced I might be in Ruby, I had to make peace with the fact that I am a beginner at Javascript and CSS. What a liberating experience that has been. The web gui’s are a bit slow, but slow is part of the territory when picking up a new thing. The browser exercises feel like training wheels, but training wheels are great for getting me to type something after every bit of information I learn, so that it sticks in my head. And here is the real revelation, the courses don’t actually take all that long. My experience still applies and lets me fly through a lot of the answers and quickly get to the things I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t care how experienced of a coder you are, if you are new to web development or new to the front-end. Give Codeacacemy and Codeschool a whirl, it is only introductory content but if the foundations is what you want to quickly get into your head, these are the best tools for the job that I have found. I would be happy to one day see a trend where there are enough of an audience to see them create some intermediate content on these type of interactive code in the browser learning sites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/06/24/you-are-never-too-experienced-for-codeacademy-or-codeschool.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/06/24/you-are-never-too-experienced-for-codeacademy-or-codeschool.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GPG error rosa Release The following signatures were invalid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Linux Mint I got this error message while trying to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/code&gt;. Here is the full error message:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;W: GPG error: http://extra.linuxmint.com rosa Release: The following signatures were invalid: BADSIG 3EE67F3D0FF405B2 Clement Lefebvre (Linux Mint Package Repository v1) &amp;lt;root@linuxmint.com&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what fixed it:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo rm -rf /var/lib/apt/lists/*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After removing those, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/code&gt; ran just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/06/19/gpg-error-the-following-signatures-were-invalid.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/06/19/gpg-error-the-following-signatures-were-invalid.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to flash my Ergodox Firmware</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My version of the firmware closely follows the partial-rewrite branch of ben-blazak.
My working branch is also the partial-rewrite branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to my Github repo
&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/dewetblomerus/ergodox-firmware&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://github.com/dewetblomerus/ergodox-firmware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps-to-set-up-when-on-a-new-computer&quot;&gt;Steps to set up when on a new computer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure all the stuff needed to compile is installed &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install gcc-avr binutils-avr avr-libc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up the Linux Dev Rules and install Teensy Loader
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjrc.com/teensy/loader_linux.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://pjrc.com/teensy/loader_linux.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps-to-edit-the-layout-and-flash-the-firmware&quot;&gt;Steps to edit the layout and flash the firmware&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edit the layout file at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/firmware/keyboard/ergodox/layout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/firmware&lt;/code&gt; and run the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; command to compile the firmware with your new layout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This will generate a new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firmware.hex&lt;/code&gt; file and place it in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/firmware&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the Teensy Loader to flash the new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firmware.hex&lt;/code&gt; file to the keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/28/how-to-flash-my-ergodox-firmware.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/28/how-to-flash-my-ergodox-firmware.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Programming Music</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I turn on music that I would normally listen to, it draws my attention, especially to the lyrics. So generally I want music with no words and I often go for electronic music because after a while it all sounds the same, which allows me to stop focusing on the music and focus 100% on the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-subscribe-to-this-rss-with-a-pod-catcher&quot;&gt;I subscribe to this rss with a pod catcher&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://musicforprogramming.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://musicforprogramming.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-i-am-home-or-somewhere-else-with-unlimited-internet-i-stream-from-one-of-these-sites&quot;&gt;When I am home or somewhere else with unlimited internet, I stream from one of these sites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://somafm.com/player/#/now-playing/groovesalad&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://somafm.com/player/#/now-playing/groovesalad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getworkdonemusic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.getworkdonemusic.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so I feel embarrased to admit that Youtube has some great study music, I have always thought that people using Youtube as a music player is ridiculous because of the wated bandwidth. Now that I found some great background study music on there, I am guilty of this as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-are-some-paid-services-i-am-considering-but-have-not-signed-up-for-any-yet&quot;&gt;Here are some paid services I am considering but have not signed up for any yet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.di.fm/search?q=goa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.di.fm/search?q=goa_blank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-other-lists-i-found-online&quot;&gt;Some other lists I found online&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/trance/comments/2s3hy0/what_are_some_of_your_favorite_uplifting_trance/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What are some of your favorite uplifting trance songs without any lyrics?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapistmagazine.com/forums/read/18.403016-Looking-for-good-ambient-trance-music-No-Vocals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Looking for good ambient/trance music, No Vocals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/11/programming-music.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/11/programming-music.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Postgres could not connect to server because rails was connecting to it on the wrong port</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So this tripped me up today and initial googling was not very helpful, maybe because I did not zero in on the right part of the error soon enough, but I hope you find this helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a new Rails app and set up a Postgres database on my development machine. Then as soon as I tried to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rake db:create&lt;/code&gt;, I got the following error&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;could not connect to server: Connection refused
    Is the server running on host &quot;localhost&quot; (127.0.0.1) and accepting
    TCP/IP connections on port 5432?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up going down a different route, trying to figure out if the server is running, googling and renaming a pid file, etc…..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally zeroed in on the port number at the end, I learned that I can check what port Postgres is listening on with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo -u postgres psql -c &quot;SHOW port;&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This showed me that postgres was running on 5433 while Rails was trying to connect to 5432. All I had to do was add a line in my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;database.yml&lt;/code&gt; to specify the port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;default: &amp;amp;default
  adapter: postgresql
  encoding: unicode
  host: localhost
  port: 5433
  username: postgres
  password: postgres
  pool: 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, my username and password is something else, but if you are setting up Postgres in development for the first time, you can get away with these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem solved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/10/postgres-could-not-connect-to-server.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/10/postgres-could-not-connect-to-server.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I used VirtualBox snapshots to create my ultimate Linux post install script</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-have-always-wanted-a-really-awesome-linux-post-install-script-to-automatically-install-and-set-up-everything-i-need-to-start-being-a-productive-web-developer-within-an-hour-after-installing-linux&quot;&gt;I have always wanted a really awesome Linux post install script to automatically install and set up everything I need to start being a productive web developer within an hour after installing Linux.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a few reasons for this:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s cool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I saw thoughtbot created an OSX laptop script (aka, it’s cool)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t like doing tedious, repetitive tasks, which is also why I love programming.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It breaks focus when I am in the middle of coding something and I need to apt-get install some dependancy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Installing stuff manually can waste a lot of time, because while I wait for it to download or install I can get distracted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have taught a lot of people to code and really love getting people started. Windows is great but I don’t do development on it, so if you want to “follow me” then I will help you set up your Linux environment so that it is ready to start coding. This means I actually get to use my install script quite often.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It gives me the freedom to try out different distros whenever I want. As long as I install Linux at the end of the day and set my script to run, I don’t lose any time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One challenge I always had with not getting my install script tuned quite the way I needed it, was that even while running a bootcamp, I use it less than once per week. So if I needed 25 iterations to get it where I wanted it, that’s over half a year. The other problem is that if something fails halfway through installing things, you can’t fix it and see it working in it’s fixed state, you have to fix it and wait for next time to see the results, which kills motivation. I was slowly making my way through this process with no end in sight when I got annoyed and decided to solve this once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-virtualbox-snapshots&quot;&gt;Enter, VirtualBox Snapshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like Git for a Virtual Machine. It allowed me take a couple of hours and run my script many times over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the steps I took:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Linux Mint in a VirtualBox (I switched from Ubuntu to Mint as my main distro this year).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a Snapshot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run my script.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When something fails I fix the part of the script that caused it to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restore to the snapshot. (This is instant on an SSD).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat steps 3-5 until the whole thing runs without any problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my current post-install script. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dewetblomerus/linux-laptop&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;linux-laptop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/24/how-i-used-virtualbox-snapshots-to-create-my-ultimate-linux-post-install-script.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/04/24/how-i-used-virtualbox-snapshots-to-create-my-ultimate-linux-post-install-script.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
